# JAMES D. HAGEMAN

jamesd@hageman.ca

1B Software Engineering | University of Waterloo | ID # 20604974 | JamesHageman on Github 416-262-9985

# **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

A highly focused software developer with advanced problem solving skills and an ability to create complex application architecture. A quick learner who absorbs new information easily with strength in rapidly prototyping a minimum viable product. Demonstrates, communicates and collaborates effectively in an agile team setting.

- 3 years developing full stack, MVC web applications with React and AngularJS
- 3 years backend development with REST API's, PHP, SQL, Node.js and Websockets
- Strong focus on building abstractions and reusable UI components in JavaScript

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

**Full Stack Web Developer,** Innovasium Digital, Markham Ontario April-September 2015; Summers 2012-14 PAAB Advertising Approval System (273 commits, 2013-2015)

- Modernized web application for PAAB that manages the submission, review and approval process for ~8000 advertising submissions/year for pharmaceutical industry
- Improved company's daily workflow by implementing real-time collaborative document annotation system with Node.js and Websockets
- Built 50+ screens for workflow, admin and reporting using AngularJS, a REST API with PHP and SQL

### Plexus Promotional Gateway v8 (289 commits, 2015)

- Improved the performance and user experience of a legacy system that processes ~\$1M of samples and promotional items per year for top pharmaceutical companies
- Rebuilt the user interface as a React web application with a modern look and feel
- Designed a powerful reusable DataGrid component with high performance with thousands of rows increasing both developer productivity and UI consistency
- Introduced modern web technologies such as React, ES6, Webpack, LESS to improve the team's code performance and quality

#### Frontend Web Development Starter Kit (2015-react-stack on Github, open source)

- Decreased the overhead of starting projects by creating a starting point for frontend web apps with a common structure and design
- Modernized our web development process by combining React, Flux MVC Architecture, BabelJS, Webpack, jQuery, Bootstrap, LESS, ESLint, NPM into one package
- Used as a baseline for 3 different portal projects for customer service, learning management, and ordering at Innovasium; currently being extended to support mobile platforms

#### **EDUCATION**

# Candidate for Bachelor of Software Engineering - University of Waterloo

2015 - 2020

• President's Scholarship of Distinction for entrance average above 95%

# Ontario Secondary School Diploma - Port Perry High School

2011 - 2015

Governor General's Award for the highest academic average

#### **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

• Passion for music performance – lead guitar, vocals, jazz, piano